Dennis Ries

Email: dtries@gmail.com | Phone: 740-818-9067 | Arvada, CO 80007

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dennis-ries/

Github: https://github.com/dtries | Website: https://github.com/dtries | Website: https://dtries.github.io/Portfolio/index.html

SUMMARY

Genuine, versatile former university professor with an enveloping enthusiasm for coding and integration of technologies that cut through complexity. Effective at combining an iterative approach with intuitive leaps to create innovative, value-added solutions. Aims to build superbly-crafted, web-based applications that engender exceptional client, company interaction.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, AJAX, Node.js, PHP, Laravel, Express.js, React.js, Database Theory, Bookshelf.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, Git, Github, Firebase, computer science fundamentals, writing tests, MATLAB

PROJECTS

Get Out and Explore | Site: https://joshspeakman.github.io/Project-1/

Role: Co-Developer | Github: https://github.com/Joshspeakman/Project-1

Encourages active exploration of a community through discovery of interesting events.

- Application requests, merges, and displays event and weather information obtained from separate API sources in a simple and elegant UI/UX. My core responsibilities included: API queries and data retrieval, UI/UX for API queries, and combined data display.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Materialize, Moment.js, Github

Far-East Showdown | Site: https://dtries.github.io/unit-4-game/

Role: *Sole Developer* | **Github**: https://github.com/dtries/unit-4-game

Fun, quick RPG game wherein a player battles three other characters individually.

- Application displays character cards for selection, moves selections to battle area, and removes defeated cards from play. Health scores and progress are tracked.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Github

Which Train When | Site: https://dtries.github.io/Train-Scheduler/

Role: Sole Developer | Github: https://github.com/dtries/Train-Scheduler

Intuitive and easy to use train schedule tracker for persons on the go.

- Application presents an intuitive interface wherein train travelers can see the current time, train arrival and related information. New trains can be added, train information is stored in a database, and arrival information is updated every minute.
- HTML5, CSS3, Firebase, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Github

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

University of Colorado-Anschutz Medical Campus – Aurora, CO

Laboratory Manager, 2017- 2018

Managed the daily operations of an NIH funded research laboratory investigating the impact of programmable hearing aid target fit on language acquisition in infants with hearing loss.

Technical duties included software installation, database queries and quality assurance, equipment calibration, and creation of automated spreadsheet processes.

Selected Accomplishments:

- Developed spreadsheet algorithms for participant recruitment tracking and scheduling that improved efficiency by approximately 25%.
- Generated effective data visualizations appearing in national/international conference presentations and published in peer reviewed, scientific journals.

Fort Hays State University – Hays, KS

Department Chair, 2016- 2017

Lead and represented a department of 11 staff and upwards of 100 students. Technical duties included working with IT professionals to implement and maintain HIPAA compliant authorized access control to data and records as well as working with faculty and staff to determine computing hardware/software needs for research, clinical, and academic endeavors.

Selected Accomplishments:

- Active member of a campus wide website reengineering committee tasked with design of an engaging UI/UX experience scalable by user type and role.
- Developed custom computer programs and UI/UX in MATLAB for research in psychological acoustics resulting in presentations at national conferences.

University of Colorado-Boulder – Boulder, CO

Adjunct Faculty/Research Contractor, 2014- 2016

Conducted data collection, database entry, and code review operations for a NIH funded project investigating hearing aid software and target prescriptions in older adults.

Selected Accomplishments:

- Reviewed computer code for the project to assist in debugging activities.
- Employed novel, custom software adaptations of traditional, paper-based tests to decrease data collection and entry time while increasing scoring accuracy.

Ohio University – Athens, OH

Faculty, 2004- 2016

Engaged actively in research, teaching, mentorship, service, and coordination in a department with over 15 staff and 350 students. Technical duties included development of custom computer coding and data tracking for multiple student projects as well as ongoing laboratory research.

Selected Accomplishments:

- Composed computer code and UI/UX for research resulting in 18 publications in scientific journals and of 23 presentations at international/national conferences.
- Mentored students in fundamental MATLAB coding for hearing research.

EDUCATION

University of Denver, Denver, CO – Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp **University of Minnesota**, Minneapolis, MN – Ph.D., Communication Sciences and Disorders **University of Minnesota**, Minneapolis, MN – M.A., Communication Sciences and Disorders **University of Minnesota**, Minneapolis, MN – B.A., Speech Communications